# Farhan Hamid

**ELECTRICAL (TELECOMMUNICATION)** ENGINEERING

frhamid2000@gmail.com 🔀

+92 0310-2699286

Rawalpindi 💡

https://www.linkedin.com/in/farhan-hamid- in a76516203/

## **PROFILE**

I am doing Bachelors in Electrical Engineering from NUST and looking forward to becoming a MERN stack developer before graduation.

I work as a front-end developer and web designer to improve the user experience on the web. I have a lot of hobbies and a strong desire to learn. I have six months of experience in front-end web frameworks, responsive web design, and development using HTML, CSS, Materialize CSS, Node.Js, MongoDB, and Express.

## **SKILLS**

MATLAB	••••	CSS	••••
Python		Javascript	••••
Wireshark	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$	Node.js	••••
Proteus		Express	••••
HTML	• • • • •	Materialize CSS	• • • • •

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Web Developer Intern

Contract.pk Aug 2022 - Sep 2022

Worked on weekly tasks and became acquainted with Git, GitHub, Materialize CSS and other frameworks. In the final week i created a Smart lawyer website that would take query from the user and answerer that according to Pakistan Panel Code.

## Cloud Engineering Intern

Pakistan Software Export Board May 2022 - Aug 2022

In this internship i learned Introduction to Cloud Computing (IaaS, PaaS, SaaS), Linux and Virtualization, Linux CLI and Package Management, Bash, User Management, System Administration, User Permission, Disk Partition, LVM, SSH server, Firewalls, Ip tables, Web Server, Cloud Computing Infrastructure; AWS, Azure, Google Cloud, AWS Cloud Practitioner, Docker, Kubernetes.

## **PROJECTS**

# Traffic light control system

#### **Control Traffic**

The LEDs get automatically switched on and off by making the corresponding port pins of the microcontroller high, based on the 8051 microcontroller and its programming was done by using KEIL software

#### Controlling fan speed with temperature

To change fan speed according to surrounding temperature Aurdino UNO and LM-34 temperature sensor were used for this project

## Fire Rooster Smart Detecting System (FYP)

#### **Detect Fire**

Working on devising a smart system which should detect and monitor potentially harmful fires through IP cameras using Artificial Intelligence algorithms.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's in Electrical (Telecommunication) Engineering

National University of Sciences & Technology (NUST) Sep 2019 - Present

#### Matriculation and Intermediate

Army Public School and College, Malir Cantt Karachi 2016 - 2019

# **AWARDS**

**HULT PRIZE MCS 2020** 

**HULT PRIZE** 

semifinalist- Presented an idea of recycling waste foods from restaurants into fertilizer and protein powder

President

**IEEE MCS NUST SB** *2022-06-25*